# RICHARD SEWARD

Loveland, CO 80537 | (970) 430-8559 | raseward14@gmail.com

## Links

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-seward-7b9336102/
- https://raseward14.github.io/Responsive-Portfolio/

• https://github.com/raseward14

## **Professional Summary**

Motivated full stack developer with a passion for lifelong learning! Specialize in utilizing multiple programming languages & tools to create interactive online platforms that draw users in with intuitive UI's. Recently received a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Denver. Well versed in fast paced work environments susceptible to ever changing client requests and processes.

#### **Technical Skills**

HTML5 | Node.js | Express | CSS3 | JavaScript | JQuery | React.js | React | JSX | MongoDB | MySQL |
Mongoose | Handlebars | Bootstrap | Materialize | APIs | Heroku | Terminal | AJAX | Restful API | ES6 |
React Hooks | JSON | Sequelize | Responsive Design | GIT | GitHub | Gitub | Bulma

# **Relevant Experience | Projects**

Tech Blog | Full Stack Developer | Deployed Link: <a href="https://mighty-taiga-53972.herokuapp.com/">https://mighty-taiga-53972.herokuapp.com/</a> | Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/raseward14/Tech\_Blog">https://github.com/raseward14/Tech\_Blog</a>

A CMS-style blog site where developers can publish their blog posts and comment on other developers' posts as well. Hosted by Heroku, this application follows the MVC pagadigm in its architectural structure, uses Handlebars.js as the templating language, Sequelize as the ORM, and the express-session npm package for authentication.

- Role: Several node package modules are utilized; express-handlebars package implements Handlebars.js for views, MySQL2 and Sequelize packages connect to a MySQL database for models, and create an Express.js API for Controllers, dotenv package is for environment variables, bcrypt package hashes passwords, and express-session and connect-session-sequelize packages add authentication.
- Utilized: Heroku, MVC paradigm, express-handlebars, MySQL2, Sequelize ORM, bcrypt, dotevn

Weather Dashboard | Full Stack Developer | Deployed Link: <a href="https://raseward14.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/">https://raseward14.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/</a> | Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/raseward14/Weather-Dashboard">https://github.com/raseward14/Weather-Dashboard</a>

Search for a city to see today's forecast, as well as the 5-day extended forecast with corresponding icons. User searches are saved as list items to revisit later.

- Role: Created HTML page styled with CSS to add Server-Side API data with bootstrap framework. Fetched data from OpenWeather to display current, and extended forecast data. Dynamically updated HTML by manipulating DOM with vanilla JavaScript to list searched cities below input field. Utilized local storage to display recently searched cities on page load.
- Utilized: HTML5, CSS3, JSON GET requests, Server-side API's; OpenWeather, JavaScript, JQuery

# **Work History**

Staffing Recruiter 08/2019 to Current

Elwood Staffing - Longmont, CO

- Interviewed (up to 40 daily), 200+ daily emails, recruit, onboard, offboard, orientation, counsel, resume building, job fairs
- Associate i9's ID verification, drug screens, background checks, and workers comp, HFWA 25+ client onboarding SOP's, P&L review, payroll
- Consistently exceeded year to date net income, 5-time Superior Customer Service award recipient

## **International English Teacher**

10/2016 to 03/2019

IQ International School – Siem Reap, Siem Reap, Cambodia

- Successfully developed clear, concise lessons, classroom management, 'Back Pocket Activities', track progress, advanced MS Excel Pivot Table, Mc at school events, filmed inspiring school videos
- Developed running club, football club, cursive writing, reading comprehension, Sport & Fitness courses, library read at home program
- Built English mathematics curriculum grades 4 9

#### **Project Management Intern**

06/2016 to 09/2016

EdVenture International – Bangkok, Bangkok, Thailand

- Humanitarian educational development Southeast Asia, project logistics
- Collected "best" photos, participant reflections, leadership workshops
- Stationed in Thailand at Bantaklang elephant village, Chiang Mai, Baan Don Chai Girls School, Bangkok, and in Cambodia at Sopheak's Friendship School and Phum Oh in Siem Reap city.

### **Education**

#### **Full Stack Web Development Certificate**

Expected in 05/2021

University of Denver - Denver, CO

• Continuing education in Full Stack Development

**BBA**: Management & Economics

12/2014

Colorado Mesa University - Grand Junction, CO

• Graduated cum laude, 3.67 GPA, Deans List Fall 2010-Fall 2014

- Men's Varsity XC/T&F Team: 4 yr.'s, Team Captain 2014
- Phi Beta Lambda: 4 yr.'s Director of Membership 2012